tl.net 2019-12-28

# Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to us. We provide this policy to better protect you, and to explain our online information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

This privacy policy applies to all Team Liquid website properties, including teamliquid.net, liquipedia.net, liquidhearth.com, liquiddota.com, liquidlegends.net, teamliquidpro.com and any standalone partner websites that are made by us.

## The Information We Collect and Use

During user registration, we collect the following information:

Username  
Email address (if provided)  
IP address  
Country

The username you supply will be used as a public identifier when posting content to our website. An email address is required to register directly on our website as login details and password reset requests will be sent to it. Your email address will never be publicly displayed on any part of the website, but it will be visible to Team Liquid staff for purposes of contacting you directly about your account and identifying common spambot emails. Your IP address is recorded and visible only to our staff for the purposes of monitoring abuse resulting from multiple registrations under the same IP address, spam bots, unsolicited advertisers, etc. Your country is shown publicly on your posts, you may update or remove the country display from you user control panel.

If you register using a 3rd party service such as a social media site (Facebook, Twitter, Twitch, Steam, etc), upon your consent that 3rd party will provide us with a unique identifier so that we may identify you on future logins. We do not store your social media username or any other details that may incidentally be provided to us when using social media logins. Your social media username will be used during the first login in order to provide you with a recommended username on our website.

As part of our site features, we offer a forum and other features on which you can freely post any text. If you choose to disclose personally identifying information, be aware that Team Liquid is a public web site and anyone is able to read your posts, so there is no expectation of privacy for user-generated content. Where applicable, we will moderate any posts that violate EU law in regards to information disclosed about other individuals.

The website features a private messaging system which allows you to send message to other users on the website. The messages you exchange over the private messaging system can only be read by the recipient user account or Team Liquid administrators. The Team Liquid administrators will only access private message details if they suspect the message might be spam / advertising or otherwise malicious in nature, or if required to do so by law. We are not responsible for any disclosure of private message contents by the recipient.

As an optional feature of the user profile page, you may upload an image such as a photo of yourself. This image will be visible to other users through your Team Liquid profile page. At any time, you can modify or delete this image through your user profile settings.

During your usage of the website, your browser will open connections and send requests to our web server. The server will log each request with your IP address, date and time, status code, browser version (user agent), HTTP referrer and the resource requested. These logs are used for internal troubleshooting purposes, such as discovering if a certain IP address is causing excessive HTTP error codes, or if a certain resource is not functioning correctly. Logs are only visible to Team Liquid system administrators and are erased after 52 days.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our site. These companies may use non-personal information in the form of tracking cookies to discover your visits to this and other web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://networkadvertising.org/).

The NAI (Network Advertising Initiative) is a cooperative group of ad serving providers. The NAI has developed a set of privacy principles to which its members adhere. The NAI is committed to provide consumers with clear explanations of Internet advertising practices and how they affect you and the Internet generally. For more information about the NAI, third party ad servers generally, and the opt-out opportunities available through the NAI, visit <http://optout.networkadvertising.org/>

## Use Of Cookies

We use a first party session cookie ("SID") to track your session across the site. This cookie is temporary and is necessary for basic functionality of the website such as maintaining your logged in status and providing security against cross site request forgery. The cookie will be deleted automatically when you close your browser. If you choose to log in to our site, we will set a first party cookie ("tlnet") that remembers your username and password, so on subsequent visits to our site you will remain logged in.

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer to help the website analyse how visitors use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. 

This website uses Google AdSense. AdSense uses cookies to help serve the ads it displays on our websites that display AdSense ads or are participating in Google certified ad networks. When you visit our websites, a cookie may be set in your browser. Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website or other websites. Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to you based on your visit to our sites and/or other sites on the Internet. You may opt out of personalized advertising from Google and other providers by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

Cookies of other third-party vendors or ad networks may also be used to serve ads on our site. These partners include Google AdSense, Google AdExchange, Tribal Fusion, RockYou and Sovrn. You may opt out of personalized advertising cookies from these partners by visiting [aboutads.info](http://www.aboutads.info/).

By accepting cookies and using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website.

## Data Security

Team Liquid runs on dedicated hosting servers which only a few trusted senior site staff have access to. Our servers are located in professionally managed and secure data centers in Canada and France. Where possible, TLS (HTTPS) is used to protect data in transit from unauthorized disclosure or modification.

## Children's Privacy

We do not allow children under the age of 13 to use our website. As there is user generated content, the site may be unsuitable for children.

## How You Can Access Or Correct Your Information

You can access and change your country, birthday and email settings through your Team Liquid profile page. To protect your privacy and security, we may take any reasonable steps we deem necessary to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections on your behalf.

## Data Protection Officer

If you have questions about your privacy or personal data on our sites, please contact our Data Protection Officer by email at privacy@teamliquid.net or via postal mail to the following address:

Data Protection Officer  
Team Liquid  
Postbus 9777  
3506 GT Utrecht  
The Netherlands
